In this lecture, I'm going to show you a quick hands-on on model
customization. So I'm on the Amazon bedrock service. So what I can do is I can just
scroll down and go to this tune custom models. So let me just click on custom models.
So here you can see custom models. So you have the distillation, supervised fine tuning and
reinforcement fine tuning. This is still new. And here, what you need to do is just click on this
create and then you can select which fine tuning approach you want to take. So you can either do
distillation job, supervised fine tuning or reinforcement fine tuning. And as I said, it's still new.
So let me just click on this distillation job. So here you can see create distillation job. So when
we create the distillation job from here, as I had shown you in the architecture, it creates a
SageMaker job in the backend. So create a smaller, faster and more cost effective model for your
use case model distillation uses synthetic data from a large foundation model teacher to fine tune
a specialized model student. So the first thing you have to do is create the job. So job name,
so I'll just give a name. So maybe I'll say demo underscore model underscore customization.
Then you can provide the tags if you want, but it's optional. Now you need to give the name
of the distilled model details, which means when the model is customized, what would be the name of
that model? So let me just give a name. So let me just say demo underscore model underscore
students. So this is going to be the name of our customized model. Then you can use gamers if you want
to encrypt your data, provide tags and so on. But we're going to skip it for now. It's optional.
Now we have to provide the details of our teacher model, which is going to be the larger model.
So here I have to select the teacher model. So if we just click on this, okay, so right now,
I think it's providing only one option to me. So let's just click on this, no, a pro, which is the
larger model. And let me just say apply. Now we have to select the student model. So if we just
click on this, so I only have two options because you're only allowed to do the distillation
from the models in the same family. So you cannot have the teacher model as no a pro and then
student model as anthropic. Okay, now I can select either no a light or no a micro. So let me just
let no a micro. Okay, now synthetic data generation model destination allows you to generate synthetic
responses from a large foundation model and use that data to fine tune a smaller model for your
specific use case. So here, you can select the max response link set the inference parameters
to influence the response generator by your teacher model. So this is the inference parameter max
length. So you can order this if you want. Okay, now we have to provide the distillation input
data set, choose a file in Estee location that either contains prompt or prompt response pairs
or invocation logs to generate synthetic data for your student model training. Now what it is saying
is to train my student model, I will need either prompts and if I just give the prompts,
then this job is going to send those prompts to my teacher model generate the prompt response
and then train my student model. The other approach is you yourself provide the prompt response.
So basically you send the prompt to the teacher model, get a response and then consolidate
all the data and provide it here on the Estee market. Now there is one more important thing you
need to remember invocation logs. So remember when we previously looked at invocation logs. So it
sends every time we let's say we have built an application and we send requests to our foundation
model. So that will be our prompt and it will also generate a response. So all that goes to the
CloudWatch logs are on an S3 bucket. So what you can do is you can also provide that data set
to teach your student model. And now why would you want to do that? Now let's say you already
built this application with the teacher model in production and you are already getting a lot
of prompts and logs etc. So you can use same logs that you already have in the Estee bucket
or CloudWatch logs to train your student model and then replace the teacher model with a student
model to reduce your latency and cost. Okay, now we have to create an S3 bucket. So now let me
just go to a new tab and I'll just click on S3 bucket or you can just search.
Now let me just click on create bucket. Make sure you are in the same region as your
bedrock service. So I'm in the U.S. East and I have to give a bucket name. So I've just said demo
model customization 767 just to give it some random numbers so that it's globally unique.
I will just click on create bucket. Okay, now this bucket is created view details. So let's
create a couple of folders create folder and let's create as input and create folder and then we'll
just create output folder. So I'll just create an output folder output. Okay, now I have the
output folder and let me just say create folder. Okay, now I have already created this
model customization distillation data set. So I'll just click on this input and then I'll just
push this file and I'll show you in a little bit what is there in this file. So I'll just say
upload. Okay, now this has been uploaded. Okay, now this is the model customization distillation
data set. Now this data set needs to be in JSON L format and it needs to follow a specific format,
otherwise it's going to fail. So the first one is schema version. So it needs to be bedrock
conversation 2024. So this is for internal usage of AWS. Maybe they will change the schema
version in future. And then next we have this system. It basically provides some context to the
student model on what this prompt and response is about. So you can see here a chat between a
maintenance engineer and AI assistant. So it's giving it some context. The assistant analyzes
manufacturing equipment logs and then it provides some more details on the context of this prompt.
Okay, next we have the roll user. So this is actually the prompt that was sent to the
teacher model. And then then the teacher model generated a response and you can see here roll
assistant and this is the response. It has generated. Now there are four things we discussed.
So the first is the schema version that is for internal AWS usage. Then we have the system
which gives some context. And then third thing is the user where we send the prompt and finally
we have the assistant which is the response to this particular prompt. Now this is the training
dataset that we are going to get from the teacher model and then this dataset we are going to use
to train the student model. Now if I just go back to our job here we have to provide our S3
location of our training data. So let me just click on browse and if I just click on creation
date and this is the bucket we created. So let me just click on this and let me just click on
input and this is going to be our input. Okay, then you can also provide the
distillation output metrics choose S3 path to store the training output metrics input data
reported sample training dataset. So I just click on this. Again creation date creation date
and this is the S3 bucket and I can just provide the location of the output folder. Okay,
now let me just continue to scroll down. Here you can provide the service access. Choose a method
to authorize bedrock using existing service rule or create a new service rule. So let me just
say created new. So let me just say demo 123 and let me just click on create job. Okay,
it's giving me an error so I cannot have underscore and let me just remove these
and let me just go click on create job again. Okay, so it's going to take a few minutes to create
the job. So here you can see new I am a role demo 123 is being created. Please stay on the page.
Okay, now it's setting up the training job. You can see here training setup and model creation
progress preparing your training environment and building your custom model through validation
setup training optimization steps. So it's going to take about two to 24 hours and then one
important thing I want to show you is setup inference. So once it trains the student model then
we had given the name of the new model. So then you have to set it up for inferencing
and if I just click on this earlier we only had the option of purchase provision throughput. So
you have to make a minimum commitment on an early basis for one to three months. But now they've
also given the option to build on demand. So here you can see the job status over you have the data
validation, data processing, training, it's still in progress and these two have not. So we'll give
you some more job details, distillation, input data set, output metrics and so on. So please remember
that training the model can be really really expensive. But I just wanted to show you how the whole
process works. Now ultimately this job is going to fail because you need minimum 100 records
for carrying out the model customization. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture
as in the next lecture. Thank you.